Bendix, Reinhard; Papers ger021
M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections & Archives
- Published and Unpublished Writings of Reinhard Bendix, 1930-1991; 3; 275 file folders
  - Full-length works, 1947-1956; 3.2; typescripts cubic ft.
    - Social Mobility in Industrial Society. Early texts by William Goldner, Seymour Lipset, Undated (Box 5 (3-Published and Unpublished Writings of Reinhard Ben), Folder 6)
    - Social Mobility in Industrial Society. Background materials, Undated (Box 5 (3-Published and Unpublished Writings of Reinhard Ben), Folder 7)
    - Max Weber. An Intellectual Portrait, 1960 (Box 5 (3-Published and Unpublished Writings of Reinhard Ben), Folder 8)
      Notes, background materials.
    - Nation Building and Citizenship, 1964 (Box 5 (3-Published and Unpublished Writings of Reinhard Ben), Folder 9)
      Notes for Chapter 4 by Brenda Thomas.
    - State and Society. A Reader in Comparative Political Sociology, 1968 (Box 5 (3-Published and Unpublished Writings of Reinhard Ben), Folder 10)
    - State and Society. A Reader in Comparative Political Sociology. Background materials, Undated (Box 5 (3-Published and Unpublished Writings of Reinhard Ben), Folder 11)
    - Embattled Reason (1970). Early version: "Distrust of Reason", 1961-1962; mimeograph and typescripts (Box 5 (3-Published and Unpublished Writings of Reinhard Ben), Folder 12)
    - Embattled Reason. Early version: "Distrust of Reason", Undated; typescripts (Box 5 (3-Published and Unpublished Writings of Reinhard Ben), Folder 13)
    - Embattled Reason. Early version: "The Belief in Science", Undated; typescript, mimeograph (Box 5 (3-Published and Unpublished Writings of Reinhard Ben), Folder 14)
    - Kings or People. Table of contents, Undated (Box 5 (3-Published and Unpublished Writings of Reinhard Ben), Folder 15)
    - Kings or People. Background materials, Undated (Box 5 (3-Published and Unpublished Writings of Reinhard Ben), Folder 16)
  - Essays and lectures, 3.3
    - "Appendix: Karl Marx on Workers and Their Intellectual Leaders", Undated; mimeograph (Box 6 (3-Published and Unpublished Writings of Reinhard Ben), Folder 1)
    - "Einige Bemerkungen zur erkenntnistheoretischen Grundlegung der Wissens-soziologie. Eine kritische Besprechung von Hans Barth 'Wahrheit und Ideologie'", Undated (Box 6 (3-Published and Unpublished Writings of Reinhard Ben), Folder 2)
      Written with Ludwig Bendix. Typescript, undated.
    - "The Field of Political Sociology" (written with Seymour Lipset), Undated; reprint (Box 6 (3-Published and Unpublished Writings of Reinhard Ben), Folder 3)
    - "Karl Marx' Theory of Social Classes" (written with Seymour Lipset), Undated; mimeograph (Box 6 (3-Published and Unpublished Writings of Reinhard Ben), Folder 4)
    - "Managerial Appeals and Enforced Industrialization", Undated; typescript (Box 6 (3-Published and Unpublished Writings of Reinhard Ben), Folder 5)
    - "Notes on a Comparative Study of the Intelligentsia", Undated; mimeograph (Box 6 (3-Published and Unpublished Writings of Reinhard Ben), Folder 6)
    - "The State and Religion: A Note on the Analysis of Max Weber", Undated; typescript (Box 6 (3-Published and Unpublished Writings of Reinhard Ben), Folder 8)
    - Miscellaneous lecture texts, handwritten, Undated (Box 6 (3-Published and Unpublished Writings of Reinhard Ben), Folder 9)
    - Miscellaneous lecture texts, 1950s-1960s; handwritten and typescript (Box 6 (3-Published and Unpublished Writings of Reinhard Ben), Folder 10)
    - Miscellaneous lecture texts, 1970s-1980s; handwritten and typescript (Box 6 (3-Published and Unpublished Writings of Reinhard Ben), Folder 11)
    - Karl Marx paper, 1943; typescript (Box 6 (3-Published and Unpublished Writings of Reinhard Ben), Folder 12)
    - Memoranda prepared for Charles Merriam, University of Chicago, 1943 (Box 6 (3-Published and Unpublished Writings of Reinhard Ben), Folder 13)
    - "The Rise and Acceptance of German Sociology". Unpublished M.A. thesis, 1943; typescript (Box 6 (3-Published and Unpublished Writings of Reinhard Ben), Folder 14)
    - "The Rise and Acceptance of German Sociology", Undated (Box 6 (3-Published and Unpublished Writings of Reinhard Ben), Folder 15)
      Reading notes.
    - "The Rise and Acceptance of German Sociology". M.A. thesis. Bound volume, 1943 March (Box 6 (3-Published and Unpublished Writings of Reinhard Ben), Folder 16)
    - Bound reprints, 1944-1952 (Box 6 (3-Published and Unpublished Writings of Reinhard Ben), Folder 17)
    - Bound reprints, 1954-1963 (Box 6 (3-Published and Unpublished Writings of Reinhard Ben), Folder 18)
    - Bound reprints, 1964-1968 (Box 6 (3-Published and Unpublished Writings of Reinhard Ben), Folder 19)
    - Bound reprints, 1948-1966; photocopies (Box 6 (3-Published and Unpublished Writings of Reinhard Ben), Folder 20)
    - "Education and the Teaching of History", 1945 January; reprint (Box 6 (3-Published and Unpublished Writings of Reinhard Ben), Folder 21)
    - "Bureaucracy and the Problem of Power", 1945; reprints (Box 6 (3-Published and Unpublished Writings of Reinhard Ben), Folder 22)
    - "Social Science and Social Action in Historical Perspective", 1946 April; reprint (Box 6 (3-Published and Unpublished Writings of Reinhard Ben), Folder 23)
    - "Max Weber's Interpretation of Conduct and History", 1946 May; typescript, reprint (Box 6 (3-Published and Unpublished Writings of Reinhard Ben), Folder 24)
    - "J.D. Kingsley's interpretation of the historical evolution of the British Civil Service", 1947 May (Box 6 (3-Published and Unpublished Writings of Reinhard Ben), Folder 25)
      Term paper typescript, University of Chicago.
    - "Bureaucracy: The Problem and its Setting", 1947 October; reprints (Box 6 (3-Published and Unpublished Writings of Reinhard Ben), Folder 26)
    - "Marx' Views on Labor Re-Examined", 1948 January; reprint (Box 6 (3-Published and Unpublished Writings of Reinhard Ben), Folder 27)
    - "Who are the Bureaucrats?", 1948 January; typescripts (Box 6 (3-Published and Unpublished Writings of Reinhard Ben), Folder 28)
    - "Who are the Bureaucrats?" Correspondence, 1947-1949 (Box 6 (3-Published and Unpublished Writings of Reinhard Ben), Folder 29)
    - "Public Administration", ca. 1948-1949 (Box 6 (3-Published and Unpublished Writings of Reinhard Ben), Folder 30)
      Unpublished typescript.
    - "Notes on Different Aspects of Problem-Solving in the History of Science", ca. 1949; typescript (Box 6 (3-Published and Unpublished Writings of Reinhard Ben), Folder 31)
    - "Primitivism, Authority, and Human Relations", 1949; reprint (Box 6 (3-Published and Unpublished Writings of Reinhard Ben), Folder 32)
    - "The Perspectives of Elton Mayo" (with Lloyd H. Fisher), 1949 November; reprint (Box 6 (3-Published and Unpublished Writings of Reinhard Ben), Folder 33)
    - "Socialism and the Theory of Bureaucracy", 1950 November; reprint (Box 6 (3-Published and Unpublished Writings of Reinhard Ben), Folder 34)
    - "The Psychological Prophecy of Doom", 1951 (Box 6 (3-Published and Unpublished Writings of Reinhard Ben), Folder 35)
    - "Some Theoretical Implications of Industrial Society". Unpublished, 1951; typescripts and notes (Box 6 (3-Published and Unpublished Writings of Reinhard Ben), Folder 36)
    - "Social Science and the Distrust of Reason". Pamphlet, 1951 (Box 6 (3-Published and Unpublished Writings of Reinhard Ben), Folder 37)
    - "The Image of Man in the Social Sciences", 1951 February; reprint (Box 6 (3-Published and Unpublished Writings of Reinhard Ben), Folder 38)
    - "Psychiatry in Prison", 1951 February; reprints (Box 6 (3-Published and Unpublished Writings of Reinhard Ben), Folder 39)
    - "Sociological and Psychiatric Modes of Analysis", 1952 (Box 6 (3-Published and Unpublished Writings of Reinhard Ben), Folder 40)
    - "Social Mobility and Occupational Career Patterns" (with Seymour M. Lipset), 1952 January; reprint (Box 6 (3-Published and Unpublished Writings of Reinhard Ben), Folder 41)
    - "Social Stratification and Political Power", 1952 June; photocopy (Box 6 (3-Published and Unpublished Writings of Reinhard Ben), Folder 42)
    - "Compliant Behavior and Individual Personality", 1952 November; reprints (Box 6 (3-Published and Unpublished Writings of Reinhard Ben), Folder 43)
    - "Social Theory and Social Reform Action in the Sociology of Louis Wirth", 1954 May; reprint (Box 6 (3-Published and Unpublished Writings of Reinhard Ben), Folder 44)
    - "Bureaucratization in Industry", 1954; reprint (Box 6 (3-Published and Unpublished Writings of Reinhard Ben), Folder 45)
    - "The Self-Legitimation of an Entrepreneurial Class: The Case of England", 1954; reprint (Box 6 (3-Published and Unpublished Writings of Reinhard Ben), Folder 46)
    - "Alexis de Tocqueville and Max Weber", ca. 1954; mimeograph (Box 6 (3-Published and Unpublished Writings of Reinhard Ben), Folder 47)
    - "Job Plans and Entry into the Labor Market" (with Seymour Lipset and F. Theodore Malm), 1955 March; reprint, typescript (Box 6 (3-Published and Unpublished Writings of Reinhard Ben), Folder 48)
    - "The Suppression of the Class Structure in East Germany", 1956; mimeograph (Box 7 (3-Published and Unpublished Writings of Reinhard Ben), Folder 1)
    - "Political Sociology" (with Seymour M. Lipset), 1957; reprint (Box 7 (3-Published and Unpublished Writings of Reinhard Ben), Folder 2)
    - "Max Webers Einfluss auf die amerikanische Soziologie" (with Günther Roth), 1959; reprint (Box 7 (3-Published and Unpublished Writings of Reinhard Ben), Folder 3)
    - "Industrialization, Ideologies, and Social Structure", 1959 October; reprint (Box 7 (3-Published and Unpublished Writings of Reinhard Ben), Folder 4)
    - "On Teaching the 'History of Social Thought'", 1960 (Box 7 (3-Published and Unpublished Writings of Reinhard Ben), Folder 5)
      Mimeograph, American Sociological Association, New York.
    - "On the Social Structure of Western Societies: Some Reflections on Comparative Analysis" (with Seymour Lipset), ca. 1960; mimeograph (Box 7 (3-Published and Unpublished Writings of Reinhard Ben), Folder 6)
    - "Social Stratification and the Political Community. An essay on the social structure of Western societies", 1960; typescript (Box 7 (3-Published and Unpublished Writings of Reinhard Ben), Folder 7)
    - "Social Stratification and the Political Community", 1960; reprint, mimeograph (Box 7 (3-Published and Unpublished Writings of Reinhard Ben), Folder 8)
    - "Social Stratification and the Political Community", Undated (Box 7 (3-Published and Unpublished Writings of Reinhard Ben), Folder 9)
      Notes, materials.
    - "The Intellectual Lineage of Max Weber", 1961 (Box 7 (3-Published and Unpublished Writings of Reinhard Ben), Folder 10)
      Typescript, Pacific Sociological Association.
    - "Notes on the Indian Political Community", 1961 December 6-1961 December 12; typescript (Box 7 (3-Published and Unpublished Writings of Reinhard Ben), Folder 11)
    - "The extension of national citizenship to the lower classes: a comparative perspective" (with Stein Rokkan, 1962; typescript and mimeograph (Box 7 (3-Published and Unpublished Writings of Reinhard Ben), Folder 12)
    - "The extension of national citizenship", Undated (Box 7 (3-Published and Unpublished Writings of Reinhard Ben), Folder 13)
    - "The Sociology of Administration", 1962 June 3; typescript (Box 7 (3-Published and Unpublished Writings of Reinhard Ben), Folder 14)
    - "A Sociologist Looks at Economic Development", 1962 June; typescript (Box 7 (3-Published and Unpublished Writings of Reinhard Ben), Folder 15)
    - "Einleitung zur deutschen Ausgabe" [Weber], ca. 1964; mimeograph (Box 7 (3-Published and Unpublished Writings of Reinhard Ben), Folder 16)
    - "The Age of Ideology: Persistent and Changing", 1964; reprint (Box 7 (3-Published and Unpublished Writings of Reinhard Ben), Folder 17)
    - "Die Kritik am American Way of Life im amerikanischen sozialwissenschaftlichen Schrifttum", 1964; reprint (Box 7 (3-Published and Unpublished Writings of Reinhard Ben), Folder 18)
    - "Cultural-Educational Mobility and Development". Conference on Social Structure and Economic Mobility in Economic Development, 1964 January; typescripts (Box 7 (3-Published and Unpublished Writings of Reinhard Ben), Folder 19)
    - "Max Webers Soziologie heute", 1964 July 7; typescript, mimeograph (Box 7 (3-Published and Unpublished Writings of Reinhard Ben), Folder 20)
    - "Max Weber's sociology today", 1964 July 7; 1965; reprint (Box 7 (3-Published and Unpublished Writings of Reinhard Ben), Folder 21)
    - "Max Weber and Jakob Burckhardt", 1964 September 2; mimeograph (Box 7 (3-Published and Unpublished Writings of Reinhard Ben), Folder 22)
    - "Authority 'and all that'", after 1965 (Box 7 (3-Published and Unpublished Writings of Reinhard Ben), Folder 23)
      Mimeograph.
    - "Max Weber's sociology today", 1965; reprint (Box 7 (3-Published and Unpublished Writings of Reinhard Ben), Folder 24)
    - "Die vergleichende Analyse historischer Wandlungen", 1965; reprint (Box 7 (3-Published and Unpublished Writings of Reinhard Ben), Folder 25)
    - Introductory comments at Edinburgh meeting, 1965 March 19-1965 March 21 (Box 7 (3-Published and Unpublished Writings of Reinhard Ben), Folder 26)
    - "Modernization and Inequality", 1965; mimeograph (Box 7 (3-Published and Unpublished Writings of Reinhard Ben), Folder 27)
    - "The Comparative Analysis of Historical Change", 1965 April 22-1965 April 24; mimeograph (Box 7 (3-Published and Unpublished Writings of Reinhard Ben), Folder 28)
    - "Vergleichende Perspektiven über die Sozialstruktur der 'Entwicklungsländer'", 1965 June 18; reprint, typescript (Box 7 (3-Published and Unpublished Writings of Reinhard Ben), Folder 29)
    - "A Case Study in Cultural and Educational Mobility: Japan and the Protestant Ethic", 1966; reprint (Box 7 (3-Published and Unpublished Writings of Reinhard Ben), Folder 30)
    - "Max Weber and Jakob Burckhardt", 1966; reprint (Box 7 (3-Published and Unpublished Writings of Reinhard Ben), Folder 31)
    - "Towards a Definition of Modernization", 1966; mimeograph (Box 7 (3-Published and Unpublished Writings of Reinhard Ben), Folder 32)
    - "In Defense of the Ivory Tower" / "The Beleaguered Ivory Tower", 1966 February 28; typescripts (Box 7 (3-Published and Unpublished Writings of Reinhard Ben), Folder 33)
      Related correspondence.
    - "In Defense of the Ivory Tower", Undated (Box 7 (3-Published and Unpublished Writings of Reinhard Ben), Folder 34)
    - "Ideology and Sociology". International Sociological Association, Evian meeting, 1966 September; mimeograph (Box 7 (3-Published and Unpublished Writings of Reinhard Ben), Folder 35)
    - Open letter (11-11-66) to student newspaper, Undated; typescript (Box 7 (3-Published and Unpublished Writings of Reinhard Ben), Folder 36)
    - "The Comparative Analysis of Historical Change", 1967; reprint (Box 7 (3-Published and Unpublished Writings of Reinhard Ben), Folder 37)
    - "Modern Society". Voice of America Forum lecture, 1967; typescript (Box 7 (3-Published and Unpublished Writings of Reinhard Ben), Folder 38)
    - "Preconditions of Development: A Comparison of Japan and Germany", 1967; reprint (Box 7 (3-Published and Unpublished Writings of Reinhard Ben), Folder 39)
    - "The Protestant Ethic -- Revisited", 1967; mimeograph (Box 7 (3-Published and Unpublished Writings of Reinhard Ben), Folder 40)
    - "Reflections on Charismatic Leadership", 1967 June; reprint (Box 7 (3-Published and Unpublished Writings of Reinhard Ben), Folder 41)
    - "Otto Hinze" entry for International Encyclopedia of the Social Sciences, 1968; typescript (Box 7 (3-Published and Unpublished Writings of Reinhard Ben), Folder 42)
    - "Max Weber" entry for International Encyclopedia of the Social Sciences, 1968; typescripts (Box 7 (3-Published and Unpublished Writings of Reinhard Ben), Folder 43)
    - "Bureaucracy", 1968; reprint (Box 7 (3-Published and Unpublished Writings of Reinhard Ben), Folder 44)
    - "Modernisierung und soziale Ungleichheit", 1968; reprint (Box 7 (3-Published and Unpublished Writings of Reinhard Ben), Folder 45)
    - "Tradition and Modernity Reconsidered", 1968; reprint (Box 7 (3-Published and Unpublished Writings of Reinhard Ben), Folder 46)
    - "Some personal reflections on the Faculty Student Commission Report", ca. February 1968; mimeograph, typescript (Box 7 (3-Published and Unpublished Writings of Reinhard Ben), Folder 47)
    - "Education Abroad Program -- Göttingen Center. Annual Report 1969-70", 1970; typescript (Box 7 (3-Published and Unpublished Writings of Reinhard Ben), Folder 48)
    - "Sociology and the Distrust of Reason", 1970; reprint (Box 7 (3-Published and Unpublished Writings of Reinhard Ben), Folder 49)
    - "Der Einzelne und die Gesellschaft", 1970; reprint (Box 7 (3-Published and Unpublished Writings of Reinhard Ben), Folder 50)
    - "Sociology and Ideology", 1970; reprint (Box 7 (3-Published and Unpublished Writings of Reinhard Ben), Folder 51)
    - "Sociology and Ideology", 1970; mimeograph (Box 7 (3-Published and Unpublished Writings of Reinhard Ben), Folder 52)
    - "Sociology and Ideology". Background materials, notes, Undated (Box 7 (3-Published and Unpublished Writings of Reinhard Ben), Folder 53)
    - "Wissenschaft als Beruf", 1970 June 21 (Box 7 (3-Published and Unpublished Writings of Reinhard Ben), Folder 54)
      Mimeograph radio text.
    - "Social and Political Changes in the Twentieth Century", 1971; reprint (Box 7 (3-Published and Unpublished Writings of Reinhard Ben), Folder 55)
    - "Social and Political Changes in the Twentieth Century". Background materials, notes, Undated (Box 7 (3-Published and Unpublished Writings of Reinhard Ben), Folder 56)
    - "Der Glaube an die Wissenschaft", 1972; typescript, reprint (Box 7 (3-Published and Unpublished Writings of Reinhard Ben), Folder 57)
    - "Science, Knowledge, and Society: Foci for Discussion" (with Ernst B. Haas). Berkeley Science Colloquium, 1973; typescript (Box 7 (3-Published and Unpublished Writings of Reinhard Ben), Folder 58)
    - "Inequality and Social Structure: A Comparison of Marx and Weber", 1974; reprint (Box 7 (3-Published and Unpublished Writings of Reinhard Ben), Folder 59)
    - Unpublished statement on membership in the Hashomer Hazair (Berlin 1935-1936), written in 1975; typescript (Box 7 (3-Published and Unpublished Writings of Reinhard Ben), Folder 60)
    - "Notes for a Conference on Women in Russia". Stanford, 1975 May 29-1975 June 1; typescript (Box 7 (3-Published and Unpublished Writings of Reinhard Ben), Folder 61)
    - "The Limits of Inequality. A comment on a paper by Bernard Barber", 1975 June; typescript (Box 7 (3-Published and Unpublished Writings of Reinhard Ben), Folder 62)
    - "Science and the Purposes of Knowledge", Summer 1975; reprint (Box 7 (3-Published and Unpublished Writings of Reinhard Ben), Folder 63)
      Also early version: "The Ideology of Science". Typescript.
    - "The Mandate to Rule: An Introduction", 1976; reprint (Box 7 (3-Published and Unpublished Writings of Reinhard Ben), Folder 64)
    - "Introduction to Hans Barth's Truth and Ideology, 1976; typescript (Box 7 (3-Published and Unpublished Writings of Reinhard Ben), Folder 65)
    - "Interdisciplinary Work in the Social Sciences", 1976 February 18 (Box 7 (3-Published and Unpublished Writings of Reinhard Ben), Folder 66)
      Notes, related correspondence.
    - "Classes, Organized Interests and Civil Society". Chicago, 1976 November; typescripts (Box 8 (3-Published and Unpublished Writings of Reinhard Ben), Folder 1)
    - "Province and Metropolis: The Case of Eighteenth-Century Germany", 1977; reprint (Box 8 (3-Published and Unpublished Writings of Reinhard Ben), Folder 2)
    - "Some Reflections on the Science Policy Colloquium", ca. 1978; typescript (Box 8 (3-Published and Unpublished Writings of Reinhard Ben), Folder 3)
    - "Das Problem des gesellschaftlichen Konsensus: Intellektuelle und andere Menschen", 1978 May 11; reprint (Box 8 (3-Published and Unpublished Writings of Reinhard Ben), Folder 4)
    - "Why Nationalism?", 1978 October; reprints, typescripts (Box 8 (3-Published and Unpublished Writings of Reinhard Ben), Folder 5)
    - "Structural Foundations of Nationalism", ca. 1978; typescript (Box 8 (3-Published and Unpublished Writings of Reinhard Ben), Folder 6)
    - "Westeuropa als Gegenstand und Quelle sozialwissenschaftlicher Forschung", German Sociological Society, 1979; typescript (Box 8 (3-Published and Unpublished Writings of Reinhard Ben), Folder 7)
    - "Western Europe as the Object and Source of Social Science Research", Winter 1979; reprint (Box 8 (3-Published and Unpublished Writings of Reinhard Ben), Folder 8)
    - "Special Knowledge and Social Isolation. Marginal men in modern society", 1980 May 25; typescript (Box 8 (3-Published and Unpublished Writings of Reinhard Ben), Folder 9)
    - "What Max Weber Means to Me", 1980 October 30-1980 October 31 (Box 8 (3-Published and Unpublished Writings of Reinhard Ben), Folder 10)
      Related correspondence
      Typescript, Max Weber Colloquium, William Patterson College of New Jersey.
    - "Wie ich zu einem amerikanischen Soziologen wurde", 1981; reprint (Box 8 (3-Published and Unpublished Writings of Reinhard Ben), Folder 11)
    - "Reflections on a Definition by Max Weber", 1982 (Box 8 (3-Published and Unpublished Writings of Reinhard Ben), Folder 12)
      Typescripts, ASA meeting.
    - "The Intellectual's Role in the Modern World", 1982 March 4; typescripts (Box 8 (3-Published and Unpublished Writings of Reinhard Ben), Folder 13)
    - "What Max Weber Means to Me?", 1983; reprint (Box 8 (3-Published and Unpublished Writings of Reinhard Ben), Folder 14)
    - "Social Theory and the Break with Tradition", 1983 (Box 8 (3-Published and Unpublished Writings of Reinhard Ben), Folder 15)
      Typescript, for Ehrmann Festschrift.
    - "The Letters of Alexis de Tocqueville", 1983; typescripts (Box 8 (3-Published and Unpublished Writings of Reinhard Ben), Folder 16)
    - "Deutschland und der Westen", 1983 December 1-1983 December 2; typescripts, reprints (Box 8 (3-Published and Unpublished Writings of Reinhard Ben), Folder 17)
    - "Deutschland und die USA: Reflexionen eines Sozialwissenschaftlers", 1983 December 8; typescript (Box 8 (3-Published and Unpublished Writings of Reinhard Ben), Folder 18)
    - "Generations as Problems of Personal Identity", 1984; typescript (Box 8 (3-Published and Unpublished Writings of Reinhard Ben), Folder 19)
    - "Reflections on Max Weber's Protestant Ethic", 1984 (Box 8 (3-Published and Unpublished Writings of Reinhard Ben), Folder 20)
      Typescript, UC Santa Cruz, Humanities Institute.
    - "Authority" / "Authorität", ca. 1985; reprint, typescripts (Box 8 (3-Published and Unpublished Writings of Reinhard Ben), Folder 21)
    - "Kommentar zu P. Rossis Beitrag", 1985; reprint (Box 8 (3-Published and Unpublished Writings of Reinhard Ben), Folder 22)
    - "Vorboten der Intoleranz im frühen Christentum", ca. 1985; typescript (Box 8 (3-Published and Unpublished Writings of Reinhard Ben), Folder 23)
    - "Umbildungen des Charisma. Überlegungen zu Max Webers Charismabegriff am Beispiel des Frühchristentums", 1985; typescripts (Box 8 (3-Published and Unpublished Writings of Reinhard Ben), Folder 24)
    - "Transformations of Charisma. Reflections on Max Weber's concept of charisma with reference to Early Christianity", 1985; typescripts (Box 8 (3-Published and Unpublished Writings of Reinhard Ben), Folder 25)
    - "Transformations of Charisma", Undated (Box 8 (3-Published and Unpublished Writings of Reinhard Ben), Folder 26)
    - "Der europäische Sonderweg", 1985 October (Box 8 (3-Published and Unpublished Writings of Reinhard Ben), Folder 27)